Hey guys, welcome to another video, so we previously discussed the cyberkill chain.
So in this video, we will discuss about the Mitrotax framework, so that was commonly used
in scheduling the EDR rules, detection engineering, MDR, XPRs, everything, everywhere
you can see the rule based on Mitrotax framework, because if you see a cyberkill chain,
there is only a seven tactics are there, right, common weaponization, delivery, seven
methods are there, but if we see in Mitrotax, there will be 14 tactics, it will be there,
okay.
This is a detailed exploration, detailed explanation, if it is comparing the difference
between the cyberkill chain and Mitrotax, Mitrotax will be a bus thing, so it will, because
it will give a detailed explanation of attacker how they will achieve their goal to attack
the organization, okay, so basically in my turn, so this is the, I am not discussing about
this kind of things and, okay, so let us, let us learn what are the things we need in
Mitrot, okay, there is a three things, one is for tactics and another one is for technique
and another one is a TT procedure, okay, tactics, techniques and procedure, okay, so basically
we will call, this is a TT, TT, TTP, yes, TT, static, technique and procedures, so we can
see the tactic is like a reconnaissance, resource development, initial access, execution,
poor system privilege, escalation, defense evasion, this all the things we can say, it
is a tactics, okay, so see in cyberkill chain, there is only a recon and we will directly
go for our pronunciation, delivery and exploration, initial access, sorry, exploitation and
initial access, but in Mitrot framework, there is lot and lot of tactics, tactics will
be there, okay, so we can learn all the tactics in a optimization, one by one, so the privilege
escalation, how they will achieve, different evasion, how they will do, everything, everything
we can see there, okay, so probably this is the things, we can, we can say this is a tactics
and insert the tactics, tactics, you can see different techniques, so if it is a reconnaissance,
how the protector will do the recon, using the active scan or which technique they will
use, gather victim information through LinkedIn or any social engineering, like exploring
the Instagram or Facebook or anything, how the protector will achieve the reconnaissance
or phishing for information like your setting some phishing link to the victim and once
a victim gets logged in, so you will get the credentials, that depends upon which technique
you are using and the procedure, sorry, and the procedures like, so if I give the execution
part, if I click on the technique, this is the execution tactics and the technique will
be the, there is wooden techniques and I will click one of the technique, so you can see
command and scripting that product, so these are the procedures, okay, procedures will give
a detailed explanation, how the goal will be, how the protector will achieve their goal,
exactly, okay, so whether they will use a PowerShell or whether they use any other visual
basics, based applications or anything, okay, so how exactly the protector will achieve
their goal in the execution, okay, so this will give a very detailed explanation comparing
to the cybercoaching, so sometime in interview, they will ask the questions like, so
whether you will use a cybercoaching or MITRE, so your answers should be a MITRE because
MITRE will give a detailed explanation of the protector, how they will operate and how
they will achieve their goal, achieve their goal to attack the organization, okay, this
will give a very detailed explanation like each and every technique that the attackers
will use for it, okay, so let me explain each and every tactics here so that you can,
you have some idea about this, okay, so let's start with the recognizance, so recognizance
is, we know it's a, it's a information gathering, so you can gather information from
any way like you can scan the machine or you can do some other recognizance like you can
use the multigo or you can go for a Facebook Instagram or whatever social, social engineering
things and social medias, so you can use any tools for your account to gather, about, gather
the victim information, okay, once you gather the victim information, you need to develop
the resource, so what are the resource you need to, you need for attacking the organization
right, so you need to develop your own program, your own code or your own malware, whatever
you can say, you have to develop that and the third thing, the initial access, the initial
access will be, how you are getting into the machine like whether you are using the phishing
or you can doing some external remote service like RDB or anything, okay, some code injections
or anything, the initial access, what techniques you are following, for example the phishing,
you are sending a spam email to your victim in the outlook and you are when the victim
click on the link, so now the code will be executed on the victim machine, so that's the
one way, so we can discuss everything in the initial access of the upcoming videos, I just
give you some examples, don't worry about that, so if you are afraid, don't worry about
that, okay, the next execution will be how you are executing your code, how you are executing
your malware instead of the machine, okay, after executing, the next technique will be
the persistence, so persistence is like when the victim shut down or restarted their
machine, so your malware will be terminated, your malware will be deleted from the memory,
so you will not get any reverse connection from the malware, so you can't able to control
the victim machine, control the target machine, so what you are doing, you need some
persistent connection from the victim machine, so you can use some techniques to be
a persistence, if the victim restarted or the machine also, you will be getting the command
and control probably, if the victim rebooted or restarted their machine, so you will
get command and connections, okay, so next thing will be the privilege escalation, privilege
escalation is like if you are in a user privilege, you can move to the administrator privilege,
it's an example of college, let me take an example of a college, so there's a student
ID and a principal head of the department, stuff, everything, everything, every people
are there, right, so if you are in a student ID, so you need to move to the principal
privilege, so you can do some techniques and you can easily get the administrator privilege
user to the administrator privilege, administrator to the super admin privilege, okay, so
you can see that in the privilege escalation tactics, and let's discuss about the defense
evasion, defense evasion is like your turning of the, if you are disabling the defenders
or you are bypassing the anti-wares platform or any EDR platform they are using, okay, so
next we have a credential access, the defense evasion is like bypassing the anti-wares
or firewalls or whatever you can call, so next thing will be a credential access, so once
you get into the machine you can steal the browser credentials, you can take the victim targeted
browser credentials, example the Facebook, Instagram passwords or the Windows machine
passwords or any passwords you want, you can gather the information, credential information
from the victim machine and discover it's like if you want to do, if you want to hack
other machines inside the organization, you can do some scanning, so what are the machines
are present inside the network and which machines will be the active directory, which
machine will be the, which machine we can hack, we can do our next exploit, next exploitations,
you can scanning the internal host basically, it's discovery like that, lateral movement
is like once you have the information, like you will get enough information from the discovery
part, like what are the machines are available in the internet, so which are the machines
are we can hack, okay, so once you got some information, you are trying to move from
one machine to another, you have done one machine, you need to hack another machine
instead of organization, so what you are doing, by using the lateral movement tactics,
you can move from one machine to another, that's how you are doing your discovery part,
so discovery, you are scanning the internal network and you are discovering what are the
machines are live in the internal network and you are hacking one by, you are going to
hack the machines one by one, okay, to one by one, inside the organization, so that's
a lateral movement, so once you get all the machines, you are collecting the information,
okay, you are collecting, so if you want to exfiltered, if you want to exfiltered the data
into the public cloud or if you want to gather all the confidential documents, informations,
videos, presentations from the company to move it to the cloud, to move it to our server,
you are collecting all the information what you want, okay, so that's basically a collection,
so you are collecting the information, whatever you want from the company, and the command
and control will be, you are using the, that party applications like the any desk, team
we were, so RDP like that, so the screen will be visible to you, okay, you can easily
control the machine from the command and control, it's like, you can execute whatever you
want, you can do whatever you want, okay, in command and control, so next we have an
exfiltration, exfiltration is like a, so you are transferring the data, so what are
the data, so you have collected and you are transferring all the data into your cloud, okay,
into your cloud platform, or into your server, into your computer, okay, so you can gather
all the credentials, for example, you gathered a, you gathered a, those are based, those
are credentials from the credential access, and you are collecting the, those are credentials
by using the exfiltration, you are uploading the username and password into your server,
so that's an exfiltration, and impact is like basically you are installing the ransomware,
and we are deleting the shadow copies, deleting the files in the organizations, deleting
the backups, and deleting everything, so doing, modifying the machine, so doing whatever
you want, okay, that's an impact, so there is a few tactics and techniques are there,
so we have seen everything, we can see the detailed attacks in practical in upcoming videos,
let's hop off this video and we will continue our discussion, our continue our practical
things in the next video, so in the next section, see you guys, I hope you have cleared
about the, you have a clear understanding about the miter attack framework, okay, so if
any of them ask the questions like, in interview like, if any of them ask like, whether
you will be using the cybercloud chain or a miter, so your answers be a miter, because
miter will give the detailed explanation of each and everything, so every tactics, techniques,
and procedures, so you can follow that, okay, so that's all guys from my side, we'll hop off,
and we will continue our practical in our next session, you guys, bye bye.